Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 1896-2021
  - Subseries IX.11. Exhibitions (Museums, Galleries, etc.), 1932-2007
    - Exhibition poster for Mr. Currier and Mr. Ives Diverting Panorama, 1932 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition of lithographs to celebrate the 200th anniversary of the birth of George Washington and the 100th birthday of Louis Maurer at The Old Print Shop. On back, "Gift of Eugenia Maurer Fuerstenberg (daughter of Louis Maurer) June 30, 1939".
    - Exhibition poster for "Forty Five Years of French Art", 1941 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster produced by W.P.A., and exhibition held at the Brooklyn Museum. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct. 3, 1941.
    - Exhibition poster for "Men Against Fire", 1942 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster made by N.Y.C. WPA War Services. Special exhibition at the Museum of the City, 5th Avenue at 104th Street. Acquisition date(?) on back, Dec. 28, 1942.
    - Exhibition poster for "Old Views of American Colleges", 1945 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition at The Grolier Club. Image is of "A Prospect of the Colleges in Cambridge in New England".
    - Exhibition poster for "History of Medicine in Art, Free Exhibition of Prints", 1946 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition held at NYU College of Medicine. Image of "Fever and Ague" by Rowlandson, 18th Century. Acquisition date(?), in pencil, April 6, 1946.
    - Exhibition poster for "Freedom Exhibit", 1950 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at Freedom House, Willkie Memorial Building, 20 West 40th Street, New York. Image is of mural by Clinton Brown. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Nov 22 1950.
    - Exhibition poster for "A Medieval Treasury: New Exhibition of Rare and Fabulous Works of Art at The Cloisters", 1951 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at The Cloisters, Fort Tryon Park. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Nov 7 1951.
    - Exhibition poster for "Art Exhibition Kingston's 300th Anniversary", 1952 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition held at George Washington School, Kingston, NY, featuring a wide diversity of American Art. Aquisition date(?) on front and back, July 1952.
    - Exhibition poster for "Summer Art Show at Hofstra College, Hempstead, L.I.", 1952 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Haydock. The Summer Art show featured masterpieces from the Metropolitan Museum of Art (El Greco, Van Dyck, Rembrandt...). Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Jul 24 1952.
    - Exhibition poster for "John James Audubon 1785-1851", 1960 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster: "Moulot imp.". Exhibition held at Centre Culturel Americain, Paris.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Landscape of Change: Views of Rural New England 1790-1865", 1976 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Old Sturbridge Village, Massachusetts. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, May 18 1976.
    - Exhibition poster for "Bevan Davies", 1976 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition held at the Broxton Gallery, Westwood, CA. Poster features photograph of building at the northeast corner of Broome Street and Broadway (see note on back). On back, stamped Mar 12 1976.
    - Exhibition poster for "American Illustration: 1800 to the Present", 1977 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at the Mint Museum of Art, sponsored by Exxon, and circulated by The American Federation of Arts.
    - Exhibition poster for "Reginald Marsh: The Art of Popular Entertainment", 1977 (Folder FF 09-27)
      The poster features a Marsh engraving, "Merry-Go-Round", 1943, NYPL. Poster numbered 25/90. The exhibition was held at the Vincent Astor Gallery, The New York Public Library at Lincoln Center. Alongside the poster is a exhibition program. On back, "Gift, Malkin, 1984".
    - Exhibition poster for "Children in America", 1978 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at The High Museum of Art, Atlanta. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Jan 20 1979.
    - Exhibition poster for "Alexander Alland", 1979 (Folder FF 09-26)
      2 copies. Poster by Permild & Rosengreen. Exhibition held at Nordjyllands Kunstmuseum and Kunstindustrimuseet. Image is of Brooklyn Bridge.
    - Exhibition poster for "Art Documentation and Computers", 1979 (Folder FF 09-26)
      3 copies. Poster by Vittorio Fiorucci. All three copies have same graphic bird image. Copy 1 has text: "Picture Division Departement de L'Iconographie; Public Archives Canada Archives publiques Canada". Copy 2 has text: "National Inventory Programme Programme du Repertoire National; National Museums Musees nationaux Canada". On back of Copy 2 "To: Gail Marciano". Copy 3 has text: "Art Documentation and Computers Ordinateurs et Normes Descriptives en Art; Novermber 1-3, 1979 Du 1 Au 3 Novembre 1979 Ottawa, Canada".
    - Exhibition poster for "Panorama of the Great Metropolis", 1980 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Pat Mulvaney and Larry Zim. Inaugural exhibit at the Zim-Lerner Design Gallery in cooperation with the New York Design Fair and featured paintings, photographs, prints, and artifacts (The Larry Zim World Fairs Collection) from the New York World Fairs of 1853, 1901, 1909,1939, and 1964.
    - Exhibition poster for "Tons of Type: American Letterpress Broadsides of the 18th and 19th Centuries", 1980 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by David Gibson. Exhibition held at The Yale Center for American Art and Material Culture. Back side has text and images.
    - Exhibition poster for "Printmaking in Canada: The Earliest Views and Portraits", 1980 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by ROM (Royal Ontario Museum) and features an image, "Notre Dame Street Montreal." published by A.Bourne Montreal, 1830. Exhibition traveled from the Royal Ontario Museum to the Musee McCord Museum to the Public Archives of Canada.
    - Exhibition poster for "P.B. Wight: Architect, Contractor, and Critic, 1838-1925", 1981 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Michael Glass (Chicago) and printed by Eastern Press (New Haven). Exhibition held at National Academy of Design, New York, and image features a proposed decoration by P.B. Wight for the central stairwell of the National Academy of Design (unexecuted), reprint courtesy of The Burnham Library of Architecture, The Art Institute of Chicago. Along with the poster is a press release about a lecture series on the exhibition. On back, in pencil, "Gift from National Academy of Design, 1981".
    - Exhibition poster for "Medicine & Pharmacy: 100 Years of Poster Art", 1981 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held in commemoration of the 100th anniversary of The Albany College of Pharmacy and held at the New York State Museum, The State Education Department. Exhibited items were from the Collection of William H. Helfand. On back, in pencil, Gift of William Helfand, October 7, 1981.
    - Exhibition poster for "Acquisitions 1973-1980. George Eastman House", 1981 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by IMP/GEH (International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House). Image is of an "Untitled" autochrome by Edward Steichen, ca. 1911, Gift of Joanna T. Steichen.
    - Exhibition poster for "Keith Haring Drawings", 1982 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition at Tony Shafrazi Gallery. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Beth Eddy 2013".
    - Exhibition poster for "Particulars: Selections From The Miller-Plummer Collection of Photography", 1983 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Robert Meyer Design, Inc. and copyrighted by IMP/GEH (International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House). Image is of "Julia Margaret Cameron, (And Enid Sang), 1874, Albumen Print."
    - Exhibition poster for "Gardens of the Gilded Age: New York State Victorian Gardens", c.1983 (Folder FF 09-26)
      "Design of Posterlog: William Padgett. Title page logo design: Beverly Giannetto." Exhibition was organized at The 1890 House Museum and Center for Victorian Arts, Cortland, NY, and circulated by the Gallery Association of New York State. Exhibition funded by grant from New York State Council on the Arts; also the Homer Garden Club, Mrs. Julian W. Davidson, Mrs. Frank A. Plummer, and the Institute of Museum Services. Support also from NEA, NEH, Amerada Hess Coporation, Hess Foundation, Lehman Brothers Kuhn Loeb, Inc., Marine Midland Bank, NY Telephone Company, JC Penney, Sykes Datatronic, Inc. Images of gardens on back.
    - Exhibition poster for "Architecture in Brooklyn: An Eclectic Overview", 1983 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at the Museum of the Borough of Brooklyn at Brooklyn College. Image is of a George B. Post watercolor drawing of Williamsburg Savings Bank, reprinted with permission of The New-York Historical Society.
    - Exhibition poster for "Palace of Commerce, The United States Custom House", 1983 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Keith Godard and Janet Giampietro of Works, Text by Deborah Nevins, and Copyright by The New York Landmarks Conservancy. The exhibition sponsored by the New York Landmarks Conservancy, funded by the NEA, the New York State Council on the Arts, and the Custom House Institute. Image of Custom House o front, images, timeline, and text on back.
    - Exhibition poster for "Phototypes, Whitney Museum of American Art, Downtown Branch", 1983 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Federal Hall National Memorial through cooperation of Federal Hall Associates and the National Park Service, Manhattan Sites. Image is a 1934 Margaret Bourke-White photograph, "Ornamental Gargoyle, Chrysler Building" The Museum of Modern Art, Gift of the photographer. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, May 12 1983.
    - Exhibition poster for "Building Brooklyn Bridge: The Design and Construction 1867-1883" (Folder FF 09-26)
      2 copies. The Centennial Exhibition was at the National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, and supported by American Society of Civil Engineers; American Society of Civil Engineers - Metropolitan Section; Citibank/Citicorp; Mueser, Rutledge, Johnston & Desimone; F.W. Roebling III; Society of Women Engineers and Steinman, Boynton, Gronquist & Birdsall.
    - Exhibition poster for "Terminal New York", 1983 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by John Feidelson; photography by Bill Jacobson. The Art Exhibition was held at the Harborside Industrial Center (Brooklyn Army Terminal) and sponsored by AAA Art, Brooklyn Art and Culture Association, Materials for the Arts, New York City Public Development Corporation, Public Art Fund, and United Color.
    - Exhibition poster for "Brooklyn Bridge: 100th Anniversary 100 Photographs", 1983 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Kari Ann Pagnano and features a photograph by Arthur Leipzig. The Group Show was held at the Midtown Y Gallery.
    - Exhibition poster for "Images of Brooklyn Bridge: A Centennial Salute by Seven Photographers", 1983 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Bill Hine and printed by Pioneer Moss Reproductions, Inc. Copyright held by The Municipal Art Society of NY which also presented the exhibition. The seven photographers were Jeff Perkell, Peter B. Kaplan, Andrew Moore, Jan Staller, Michael George, Mark Feldstein, and Bill Hine. Curated by Mary Black.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Naval War College: A Century of Excellence", 1984 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibitions commemorating the 100th anniversary of the College and the history of the Navy in Narragansett Bay. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Feb 5 1985.
    - Exhibition poster for "Made on Staten Island: Agriculture, Industry, and Suburban Living in the City (1800-1984) (Folder FF 09-26)
      Inaugural exhbition held at The Historical Museum at Richmondtown, Staten Island Historical Society/Richmondtown Restoration. Grants provided by New York State Council on the Arts and J.M. Kaplan Fund. On back, in pencil, "November 1984 Gift of Charles Sachs, Staten Is. Hist. Soc."
    - Exhibition poster for "The Legacy of Lafayette", 1984 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Leone Design Group. Image of Lafayette - "B.leClair after L.Barre. Marquis de la Fayette ... gift of D. Weston Darby, Jr., 1983. Fraunces Tavern Museum". Exhibition held at Fraunces Tavern Museum, owned and operated by the Sons of the Revolution in the State of New York, Inc. On back, "Gift of Jean Burnham Nov 01 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Art of Politics", 1984 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Pushpin, Lubalin, Peckolick, Inc. Exhibition held at Museum of the Borough of Brooklyn, Brooklyn College. Poster designed to look like newpaper frontpage. Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Oct 16 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for Louis Jay Suckle - Cafeteria: Portraits from Dubrow's", 1984 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster by WalkerPrint, London. Exhibition held at Popular Photography on Park Avenue. On back, stamped Sep 14 1984.
    - Exhibition poster for "American Prints: 1914-1941", 1985 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Carl Zahn and printed by The Meriden Gravure Co., Connecticut. Copyrighted by Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (also exhibit held there) and image is of George Bellows' "A Stag at Sharkey's" 1917. Lithograph. Bequest of W.G.Russell Allen.
    - Exhibition poster for "Twentieth-Century Afro-American Artists", 1985 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Gianettino & Meredith, Inc., and Photo of artwork, "Fort Jesus (Totem) 1984" by Vincent Smith, by Sarah Wells. Exhibition held at The Newark Museum.
    - Exhibition poster for "Wine Celebration and Ceremony", 1985 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition held at Cooper-Hewitt Museum, The Smithsonian Institute's National Museum of Design, and made possible by grant from Moet & Chandon.
    - "The George Washington Bridge: Photographed by Paula Barr during the Winter Solstice 1986" (Folder FF 09-27)
      "Printed by Rapoport; separations by Accent on Color". A note from the photographer ia attached.
    - Exhibition poster for "Walker Evans", 1987 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House, Rochester (and exhibition held there), published by Artistworks, Landsdowne, PA., and printed at Virginia Lithograph. Image is of a 1936 Walker Evans photograph, "Roadside Stand, Vicinity - Birmingham, Alabama".
    - Exhibition poster for "Thus United Free: New Jersey in the Age of the Constitution", 1987 (Folder FF 09-26)
      "Poster designed bby Vincent Ciulla Design Associates, Inc.,New York, incorporating 'Washington's Reception on the Bridge at Trenton in 1789 on his Way to be Inaugurated First President of the U.S.' ...engraving on paper by Thomas Kelley...". Poster copyrighted by The New Jersey Historical Society and exhibition held there.
    - Exhibition poster for "Daniel Hauben: City Life", 1987 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster designed by Ruby Shoes Studio, and exhibition held at The Bronx Museum of the Arts with grants provided by the NEA, New York State Council on the Arts, and the Department of Cultural Affairs of the City of New York. Image: "View of 233rd Street and Broadway". Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Dec 19 1987.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Varieties of Medical Ephemera", 1987 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Jessica Helfand and Sheena Calvert. The exhibition was held at the Cushing Rotunda at Yale University School of Medicine and was from the collection of William H. Helfand. On back: Gift of Wm. Helfand and stamped Dec 22 1987.
    - Exhibition poster for "Africans in the New World 1493-1834", 1988 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Poster designed by Gilbert Associates. Exhibition was held at the John Carter Brown Library at Brown University and the exhibition program included two lectures by Dr. Larissa Brown and Prof. Franklin W. Knight. On back, stamped Mar 4 1988.
    - Exhibition poster for "A.J. Davis and American Classicism", 1989 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition presented by Historic Hudson Valley and held at Federal Hall National Memorial at corner of Wall and Nassau Streets. Image is of the Custom House (New York) and courtesy of Avery Architectural and Fine Arts Library, Columbia University.
    - Exhibition poster for "Irwin Silver", 1989 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at the American Vision Gallery and the poster was copyrighted by the American Vision Gallery, Inc., and distributed by Bruce Teleky, Inc. The poster features a Irwin Silver photograph, "Newsstand, Brooklyn, New York, 1986".
    - Exhibition poster for "Neighbors", 1990 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Exhibition organized by the Smithsonian Institute Traveling Exhibition Service and the USSR Ministry of Culture in association with Seattle Organizing Committee for the 1990 Goodwill Games and Seattle Art Museum and made possible by The Boeing Company. Image is of "The Strastnoy (Holy) Boulevard" by Nisson Shifrin, 1926.
    - Exhibition poster for "Invention Spirits", 1990 (Folder FF 09-27)
      The poster is a reproduction of a photograph by Morris Huberland, "Shoe Shine Boys, N.Y.C. 40's". A note from the photographer explains that the photograph was first exhibited at the New-York Historical Society in 1978. The Society has several works by the photographer in its collection.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Picture of Health: Images of Medicine and Health", 1991 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by Philadelphia Museum of Art. Exhibition from the collection of William H. Helfand held at the Philadelphia Museum of Art and sponsored by a grant from Merck & Co., Inc., in honor of its Centennial. Images are of a Hibbard's Rheumatic Syrup and Plaster trade card, a Office Medical poster, a Dr. Dessauer's Touring Apotheke poster, and a Pastilles Valda poster.
    - Exhibition poster for "An Enduring Interest: The Photographs of Alexander Gardner", 1991 (Folder FF 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by The Chrysler Museum and exhibition organized by The Chrysler Museum, Norfolk, Virginia. Image, "Abraham Lincoln, November 8, 1863" from the collection of D. Mark Katz.
    - Exhibition poster for "New York Public Library Recent Acquisitions: Photography", 1992 (Folder FF 09-27)
      2 copies. The poster features a silver gelatin photoprint by John Albok, "Launching (Central Park, New York, 1937)". The print is in the Photography Collection, The Miriam and Ira D. Wallach Division of Art, Prints and Photographs and is a gift of, and reproduced by permission of, Ilona Albok Vitarius. The exhibit was made possible by a generous gift of Miriam and Ira D. Wallach.
    - Series of Exhibition posters for "The Art of Persuasion", 2006 (Folder FF 09-27)
      The exhibition was presented by the New York Society of Etchers and held at The National Arts Club. 2 copies of the Will Barnet "Peace" poster featuring two doves. A Frances Jetter poster. A Marshall Arisman poster. An Ann Chernow poster. A Zev Deans poster.
    - Exhibition poster for "Nan Goldin, 1972-74 and The Other Side: A Slide Installation", 2007 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at the Matthew Marks Gallery.
    - Exhibition poster for "Darren Almond", 2007 (Folder FF 09-27)
      Exhibition held at the Matthew Marks Gallery.
  - Subseries IX.12. Scouts, 1917-1925
    - "Make the Next Generation Safe. Help the Boy Scouts of America.", 1917 (Folder FF 09-12)
      2 copies. Poster printed by Franklin Printing Co., Philadelphia. Artist: W AAP Y. Copy 1: Acquisition date (?) on back, Mar. 31, 1942.
    - "for a better Womanhood" Girl Scouts Campaign poster, 1919 (Folder FF 09-12)
      3 copies. Poster designed by Lestor Ralph and copyrighted in 1919 by Girl Scouts, Inc. On Copy 1, stamped on back: "E.B. Child Collection. Feb 1946". On Copy 2, stamped on front: "BCL".
    - "Boost! Boy Scout Week", ca. 1919 (Folder FF 09-12)
      2 copies. The image of the scout featured in the poster is by Norman Rockwell. Copy 1: Acquisition date (?) on back, Mar. 31, 1942.
    - "We Want You for Our Scoutmaster" Boy Scouts of America, ca. 1925 (Folder FF 09-12)
      Poster designed by Ernest Fuhr and printed by Lutz & Sheinkman, Lithographers, New York. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back, Feb 28 1925.
  - Subseries IX.13. Statue of Liberty, 1976-1986
    - Macy's Fourth of July Fireworks advertisement, 1976 (Folder FF 09-23)
      Poster copyrighted by Macy's New York, and image featuring Statue of Liberty and fireworks by Griesbach-Martucci.
    - NPS Call for Comments on the planning alternatives for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island, 1981 (Folder FF 09-23)
      Poster was published by the U.S. Department of the Interior/ National Park Service with publication services provided by the graphics and editorial staffs of the Denver Service Center. Poster was sent to the Historical Society. The two-sided poster includes a fairly comprehensive list of the National Park Service's preferred plans and alternatives for its project to preserve Ellis Island and the Statue of Liberty.
    - "Keep the Torch Lit" Statue of Liberty Centennial poster, 1982 (Folder FF 09-23)
      Poster designed by S.L./E.I. Foundation, Inc. Poster is red and blue on a white background with the face and crown of the Statue of Liberty and "1886 CENTENNIAL 1986" featured. On back, stamped, Feb 16 1985.
    - "Statue of Liberty 1984" (Folder FF 09-23)
      Photograph of Statue of Liberty with scaffolding by Fred R. Tannery (Poster is also signed by Tannery). Copyright by Eye of a Camera Production and published bby Harbert Corporation, NYC. On back, stamped, Jan 12 1985.
    - "Lady of Liberty: A Proud Heritage", 1986 (Folder FF 09-23)
      Poster published by Federated-Fry Metals, Altoona, Pennsylvania, from an oil painting by George Plataz in 1986.
  - Subseries IX.14. 9/11 (incl posters by Creative Time), 2001-2006
    - "Faces of Ground Zero -- Giant Polaroid Collection", c. 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      3 copies. Poster created and signed by Joe McNally Photography. In note at bottom - the reproduced images were created by only life-sized Polaroid camera.
    - "September 11th", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      Giclee print poster (3/6) created by Erica Hart in 2001. Includes images of hands, rubble, fire, and the statue of Liberty. On back, "Gift of Mrs. Erica Hart, 2002".
    - "Don't Tread on Me", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster created and signed by Boyd G. Sharp. Images include twin towers, bald eaagle, American flag, Liberty torch, and firefighter. On back, "Gift 2014".
    - "Firefighters Angel. The Bravest of the Brave. Thank You for the Lives You Save.", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      The poster was created by ArtAid. It includes the names of the firefighters who died on 9.11.01. The image is the Firefighters Angel.
    - "Fifth Avenue ... September 2001" (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster was created and signed by Libby Lesher with contributions going to United Firefighters Association. The images are of buildings along Fifth Avenue in Manhattan flying American flags.
    - "WTC 1976-2001" (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster created by Sandy Walker after an ink drawing, "World Trade Center" 1980 by Sandy Walker. An accompanying note from the artist explains the gift of the posters in relation to the WTC show organnized by The New-York Historical Society.
    - "World Trade Center 2001. One Nation, Indivisible." (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster created by Everen T. Brown. Photographic image of Manhattan from the top of the World Trade Tower with an American flag.
    - "We Will Always Remember Where We Were And How We Felt - We Shall Never Forget How We Feel.", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)
      Poster created and signed by Michael Joseph. Poster includes image of the World Trade Center with a Cross between the towers and a raised impression of the Manhattan skyline with the World Trade Center.
    - "Ground Zero 9/11/01", 2001 (Folder FF 09-20)